<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Development on Arn Kenneth Catabay</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/categories/web-development/</link><description>Recent content in Web Development on Arn Kenneth Catabay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 05:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/categories/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Landing_page</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/landing_page/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 05:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/landing_page/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/landing_page/landingpage.png" alt="Featured image of post Landing_page" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This landing page was created as the companion website for our mobile game. It uses Firebase to connect and synchronize data with the game, ensuring seamless integration between both platforms. The site highlights the game’s key features, provides an overview of the gameplay experience, and offers users the option to download the mobile app. Both the website and the mobile application are currently under active development, with continuous improvements being made to enhance functionality and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dashboard</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 06:33:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/dashboard/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/dashboard/dashboard.png" alt="Featured image of post Dashboard" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This dashboard was developed as part of our quiz game to enable instructors to monitor student progress and performance in real time. It is powered by Firebase as the primary database, providing secure and efficient data management between the game and the dashboard. Teacher accounts are manually managed by the developers to maintain system security, preventing unauthorized access and ensuring that only verified instructors can create and manage classes. This approach enhances both data integrity and overall platform security.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Porfolio</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/porfolio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/porfolio/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/porfolio/portfolio.png" alt="Featured image of post Porfolio" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my personal portfolio, designed and built using Hugo. I chose Hugo because it’s simple to work with, lightning-fast, and gives me full control over how I design and organize my content. It’s a great tool that lets me focus more on creativity and less on setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the project repository on GitHub: &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/AkKennesu/portfolio" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Portfolio using HUGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Entertainment_Website</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/entertainment_website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/entertainment_website/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/entertainment_website/entertainment.png" alt="Featured image of post Entertainment_Website" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project was developed as part of our Web Development course — a comprehensive, 100-page front-end entertainment website built using HTML5, Bootstrap 5, and JavaScript. The site features a responsive design, dynamic components, and an engaging user interface aimed at delivering an interactive browsing experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the project repository on GitHub: &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/AkKennesu/Weebu-Entertainment-website" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Weebu Entertainment Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>