<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Arn Kenneth Catabay</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Arn Kenneth Catabay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 05:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Landing_page</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/landing_page/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 05:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/landing_page/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/landing_page/landingpage.png" alt="Featured image of post Landing_page" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This landing page was created as the companion website for our mobile game. It uses Firebase to connect and synchronize data with the game, ensuring seamless integration between both platforms. The site highlights the game’s key features, provides an overview of the gameplay experience, and offers users the option to download the mobile app. Both the website and the mobile application are currently under active development, with continuous improvements being made to enhance functionality and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dashboard</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 06:33:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/dashboard/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/dashboard/dashboard.png" alt="Featured image of post Dashboard" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This dashboard was developed as part of our quiz game to enable instructors to monitor student progress and performance in real time. It is powered by Firebase as the primary database, providing secure and efficient data management between the game and the dashboard. Teacher accounts are manually managed by the developers to maintain system security, preventing unauthorized access and ensuring that only verified instructors can create and manage classes. This approach enhances both data integrity and overall platform security.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Android_quiz_game</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/android_quiz_game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 04:48:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/android_quiz_game/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/android_quiz_game/game_screenshot.png" alt="Featured image of post Android_quiz_game" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of my journey as an IT student, I developed an educational quiz game designed to make learning more interactive and enjoyable for BSIT students. The goal was simple — to help students catch up on lessons while having fun at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game was built using Unity Hub, Firebase, and C#, combining smooth gameplay with reliable data management and multiplayer capabilities. One of its key features is its flexibility — it can be played both offline and online. In online mode, students can connect, play, and compete with their friends or classmates, fostering collaboration and a sense of friendly competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project allowed me to explore game-based learning as a creative way to make studying more engaging, while also strengthening my skills in game development, UI design, and real-time data integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Porfolio</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/porfolio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/porfolio/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/porfolio/portfolio.png" alt="Featured image of post Porfolio" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my personal portfolio, designed and built using Hugo. I chose Hugo because it’s simple to work with, lightning-fast, and gives me full control over how I design and organize my content. It’s a great tool that lets me focus more on creativity and less on setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the project repository on GitHub: &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/AkKennesu/portfolio" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Portfolio using HUGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Java_ecert</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/java_ecert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/java_ecert/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/java_ecert/javacert.png" alt="Featured image of post Java_ecert" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-introduction-to-java-training"&gt;My Introduction to Java training
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, I successfully earned a Java Programming E-Certificate after completing an intensive three-day online training program. The training focused on the core concepts of Java — from basic syntax and object-oriented programming principles to hands-on coding exercises and mini-projects that tested logic and problem-solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the training, I gained a deeper understanding of how Java powers many enterprise applications and platforms. The sessions also covered practical applications such as building simple console programs, working with classes and inheritance, and understanding data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earning this certification not only strengthened my foundation in programming but also reinforced my passion for software development. It gave me the confidence to explore more advanced topics and apply Java in real-world projects, including backend development and Android app programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience was a great milestone in my learning journey, reminding me that consistent effort and curiosity can turn short-term training into long-term skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introduction_to_Datascience</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/introduction_to_datascience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/introduction_to_datascience/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/introduction_to_datascience/dscert.png" alt="Featured image of post Introduction_to_Datascience" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-introduction-to-data-science-training"&gt;My Introduction to data science training
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In July 2023, I earned my &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Data Science Certificate&lt;/strong&gt; through a &lt;strong&gt;7-day online training program on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt;. The course provided a comprehensive overview of the &lt;strong&gt;fundamentals of data science&lt;/strong&gt;, covering essential topics such as data collection, cleaning, analysis, and visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the training, I learned how to apply &lt;strong&gt;data-driven thinking&lt;/strong&gt; to real-world problems and gained hands-on experience using &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;popular data analysis libraries&lt;/strong&gt;. The lessons also introduced key concepts in &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;, helping me understand how algorithms can be used to extract insights and make predictions from data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This certification strengthened my analytical mindset and deepened my interest in the field of data science. It also inspired me to continue exploring advanced topics like predictive modeling, statistical analysis, and data visualization tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completing this program reminded me of how powerful data can be when used effectively — not just to understand trends, but to make smarter and more impactful decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is data science</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/what-is-data-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/what-is-data-science/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/what-is-data-science/ds2cert.png" alt="Featured image of post What is data science" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-data-science-seminar-experience"&gt;My Data Science Seminar Experience
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May 2023, I participated in a &lt;strong&gt;one-week seminar on Data Science&lt;/strong&gt; that provided an insightful introduction to the field and its practical applications. The seminar focused on understanding &lt;strong&gt;what Data Science is&lt;/strong&gt;, its importance in today’s digital world, and the various &lt;strong&gt;tools and technologies&lt;/strong&gt; used by data professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the sessions, we explored key platforms and libraries such as &lt;strong&gt;Anaconda&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Pandas&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;NumPy&lt;/strong&gt;, which are essential for data analysis and manipulation in Python. The seminar also covered fundamental concepts like &lt;strong&gt;data preprocessing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;visualization&lt;/strong&gt;, and the role of data in decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience helped me gain a clearer understanding of how data science combines statistics, programming, and analytical thinking to solve real-world problems. It also sparked my curiosity to dive deeper into the field, especially in areas like &lt;strong&gt;data visualization&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending this seminar was a valuable opportunity to strengthen my technical foundation and connect theoretical concepts with practical data tools used in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SoundTrax_HiFid</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/soundtrax_hifid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/soundtrax_hifid/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/soundtrax_hifid/soundtrax.png" alt="Featured image of post SoundTrax_HiFid" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project showcases a high-fidelity music app prototype designed in &lt;strong&gt;Figma&lt;/strong&gt;, emphasizing a clean, user-friendly interface and a seamless &lt;strong&gt;UI/UX flow&lt;/strong&gt;. The app features intuitive navigation tabs for exploring different music genres, offering users an enjoyable and effortless browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the project design on Figma: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.figma.com/design/xFPixY9QW90BqUjcQiJ3Ri/SoundTrax-Hi-Fid?node-id=0-1&amp;amp;t=iywuxveIamPc2JkP-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;SoundTrax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Entertainment_Website</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/entertainment_website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/entertainment_website/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/entertainment_website/entertainment.png" alt="Featured image of post Entertainment_Website" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project was developed as part of our Web Development course — a comprehensive, 100-page front-end entertainment website built using HTML5, Bootstrap 5, and JavaScript. The site features a responsive design, dynamic components, and an engaging user interface aimed at delivering an interactive browsing experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the project repository on GitHub: &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/AkKennesu/Weebu-Entertainment-website" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Weebu Entertainment Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DiscordBot</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/discordbot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/discordbot/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/discordbot/dcbot.png" alt="Featured image of post DiscordBot" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Discord bot was developed to provide music playback functionality within voice channels. It utilizes the YouTube API to stream audio directly in Voice Chat and supports Spotify links by converting track titles into searchable YouTube queries for playback. Additionally, the bot integrates the Tenor API to search and share GIFs within chats, enhancing user interaction and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the project repository on GitHub: &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/AkKennesu/Discord-bot" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Discord Music Bot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>