<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OOP Java on Arn Kenneth Catabay</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/categories/oop-java/</link><description>Recent content in OOP Java on Arn Kenneth Catabay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/categories/oop-java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Java_ecert</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/java_ecert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/java_ecert/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/java_ecert/javacert.png" alt="Featured image of post Java_ecert" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-introduction-to-java-training"&gt;My Introduction to Java training
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, I successfully earned a Java Programming E-Certificate after completing an intensive three-day online training program. The training focused on the core concepts of Java — from basic syntax and object-oriented programming principles to hands-on coding exercises and mini-projects that tested logic and problem-solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the training, I gained a deeper understanding of how Java powers many enterprise applications and platforms. The sessions also covered practical applications such as building simple console programs, working with classes and inheritance, and understanding data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earning this certification not only strengthened my foundation in programming but also reinforced my passion for software development. It gave me the confidence to explore more advanced topics and apply Java in real-world projects, including backend development and Android app programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience was a great milestone in my learning journey, reminding me that consistent effort and curiosity can turn short-term training into long-term skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>