<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science on Arn Kenneth Catabay</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/categories/data-science/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science on Arn Kenneth Catabay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 08:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction_to_Datascience</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/introduction_to_datascience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/introduction_to_datascience/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/introduction_to_datascience/dscert.png" alt="Featured image of post Introduction_to_Datascience" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-introduction-to-data-science-training"&gt;My Introduction to data science training
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In July 2023, I earned my &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Data Science Certificate&lt;/strong&gt; through a &lt;strong&gt;7-day online training program on Coursera&lt;/strong&gt;. The course provided a comprehensive overview of the &lt;strong&gt;fundamentals of data science&lt;/strong&gt;, covering essential topics such as data collection, cleaning, analysis, and visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the training, I learned how to apply &lt;strong&gt;data-driven thinking&lt;/strong&gt; to real-world problems and gained hands-on experience using &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;popular data analysis libraries&lt;/strong&gt;. The lessons also introduced key concepts in &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;, helping me understand how algorithms can be used to extract insights and make predictions from data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This certification strengthened my analytical mindset and deepened my interest in the field of data science. It also inspired me to continue exploring advanced topics like predictive modeling, statistical analysis, and data visualization tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completing this program reminded me of how powerful data can be when used effectively — not just to understand trends, but to make smarter and more impactful decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is data science</title><link>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/what-is-data-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/what-is-data-science/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://AkKennesu.github.io/portfolio/p/what-is-data-science/ds2cert.png" alt="Featured image of post What is data science" /&gt;&lt;h3 id="my-data-science-seminar-experience"&gt;My Data Science Seminar Experience
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In May 2023, I participated in a &lt;strong&gt;one-week seminar on Data Science&lt;/strong&gt; that provided an insightful introduction to the field and its practical applications. The seminar focused on understanding &lt;strong&gt;what Data Science is&lt;/strong&gt;, its importance in today’s digital world, and the various &lt;strong&gt;tools and technologies&lt;/strong&gt; used by data professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the sessions, we explored key platforms and libraries such as &lt;strong&gt;Anaconda&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Pandas&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;NumPy&lt;/strong&gt;, which are essential for data analysis and manipulation in Python. The seminar also covered fundamental concepts like &lt;strong&gt;data preprocessing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;visualization&lt;/strong&gt;, and the role of data in decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience helped me gain a clearer understanding of how data science combines statistics, programming, and analytical thinking to solve real-world problems. It also sparked my curiosity to dive deeper into the field, especially in areas like &lt;strong&gt;data visualization&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending this seminar was a valuable opportunity to strengthen my technical foundation and connect theoretical concepts with practical data tools used in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>